Guide to the Papers of Rev. Richards A. Zariņš, 1883-2008 M1938
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 11. Printed material
  - Serial publications: Newspapers, journals, bulletins and related materials
    - Information on Conditions behind the Iron Curtain. Stockholm, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      1950. N 1, 2, 3, 10/11, 14
    - Latvju Balss Trimdā. Ņujorka, 1950. N 1 (Box 97, Folder 3)
      Published by Latvian National Action
    - Dānijas Latviešu Informācijas Biļetens. Kopenhagena, 1950. N 20 (Flat-box 95, Folder 8)
    - The Baltic Peoples Want to Exist. Germany, 1950, N 1, 4 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Raksti: Amerikas Latviešu Jaunatnes Apvienības izdevums. Danville, Pa, 1952. N 2, 3, 4, 5 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Newsletter From Behind the Iron Curtain: Reports on Communist Activities in Eastern Europe. Stockholm, 1952. N 277/278 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Latvju Sieviete. Minneapolis, MN, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Baznīcas Ziņas. Brooklyn, NY, 1951-1967 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Baznīcas Ziņas. Brooklyn, NY, 1972-1988 (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Baznīcas Ziņas. Brooklyn, NY, 1991-2000 (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Friend of Home. Chicago. Ill, 1953. N 3 (Box 97, Folder 11)
      English translation of the Latvian paper Mājas Draugs
    - Baznīcas Ziņas. Strathmore, Victoria, Australia. 1953. N 26, 28/29 (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Latvija: Literārs un Informatīvs Žurnāls = Letonia: Revista Literaria e Informativa. Buenos Aires. 1954, N 205, 206 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Okupētā Latvija: informacijas biļetens. Stockholm, 1954. N 4, 5, 6. 1958. N 5 (Flat-box 95, Folder 9)
    - ACEN News: a Monthly Review of the Activities of the Assembly of Captive European Nations. New York, 1955/56, 1967, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 14)
      1955/56. N 9-10, 1967. N 127, 1969. N 142
    - Daugavas Vanagi. Augustdorf bei Detmold, North Rhine-Westphalia, 1955, N 6 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Informationsblatt für die Gemeinden in den niederdeutschen lutherischen Landeskirchen. Hamburg, 1956. N 17 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Baznīcas Vēstis. London, 1957. N 9/17 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Latviešu Akadēmiskās Ziņas: Latviešu Akadēmisko Mācības Spēku Apvienības izdevums. New York, 1957. N 10 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Kara Invalīds: Latviešu kara invalīdu Apvienības izdevums. Hamburg, 1957. N 1 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Ceļa Biedrs: Menešraksts Kristīgai Dzīvei. Minneapolis, Minn., 1956-1960 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      1956. N 1, 1958. N 1-10, 1959. N 1-10, 1960. 1-10, 1967. N 8
    - Ev. Lut. Ticīgiem Latviešiem Venezuelā. 1957. N 59/60, 1969. N 198 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Die Entwicklung und Organisation der Ev. Lutherischen Kirche in Venezuela. [Place of publication not identified], 1968 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Par Atgriešanos Dzimtenē. [Place of publication not identified], 1957. N 27 (Flat-box 94, Folder 4)
    - Life. New York. January 12, 1958 (Flat-box 94, Folder 5)
      The issue of the magazine starts new series The Russian Revolution.
    - Trimdas Draudzes Vēstnesis: Londonas Latviešu Draudzes izdevums = Latvian lutheran parish news. Lpndona, 1959. N 18 (Flat-box 94, Folder 6)
    - Bitīte: Mēnešrakstiņš Rātniem Bērniem. Minneapolis, Minn, 1962. N 11, 12, 1963. N 5, 7 (Flat-box 98, Folder 3)
    - Pie Svētavota: Reliģisks Laikraksts Latvieu Ev.-lut. Draudzēm. Sennestadt, North Rhine-Westphalia, 1963. N 4, 1965. N 3 (Flat-box 98, Folder 4)
    - Rūgtais Apinis. Stokholma, 1963. N 4 (Flat-box 98, Folder 5)
    - News Bulletin: Americans for Congressional Action to Free the Baltic States. 1964-1966 (Flat-box 98, Folder 6)
      1964. N 2, 1965. N 2, 1966. N 1, 2
    - Dziesmuvaras Vēstnesis. Ņujorka, 1960. N 7, 1965. N 10 (Flat-box 98, Folder 7)
    - Daily News. New York, June 21, 1965 (Flat-box 96, Folder 7)
    - Yesterday and Today. Indianapolis, Ind, 1965. N 1, 1966. N 2 (Flat-box 98, Folder 8)
    - Baltische Hefte. Hannover-Döhren, sonderdruck aus Band 11, 1966 (Flat-box 98, Folder 9)
    - Mitteilungen aus Baltischem Leben. München, 1966. N 3 (Flat-box 98, Folder 9)
    - Mare Balticum. Hamburg, 1966, Heft 2 (Flat-box 98, Folder 9)
    - Dzimtenes Balss. Rīga, 1967. N 3, 35, 1979. N 1 (Flat-box 98, Folder 10)
    - Seši kā: kas kā kapēc kur kad ko: apkārtraksts jaunatnei Kanādā. Willowdale, Ontario, 1969. N 4 (Flat-box 98, Folder 11)
    - Aglonas Vēstnesis. Chicago, Ill., 1971. N 3 (Flat-box 98, Folder 12)
    - Raksti: Pielikums laikrakstam Latvija Amerikā. Toronto, 1973, 1-9, 11, 12 (Flat-box 98, Folder 13)
      Latviešu Preses Biedrības izdevums
    - Latvietis Latvietim: Vēstule Latviešiem Latvijā no Latviešiem Trimdā. Washington, DC, 1974-1975 (Flat-box 98, Folder 14)
      1974. N 1-3, 1975. N 4-5, 1977. N 8
    - Brīvība: Latvijas Sociāldemokrātiskās Strādnieku Partijas mēnešraksts = Freedom. Stokholma, 1976-1992 (Flat-box 98, Folder 15)
      1976. N 1-3, 1978. N 8, 1979. N 1-5, 1984. N 5, 8, 9, 1985. N 1, 7, 1986. N 3, 1987. N 3, 1988. 1-5, 1989. N 1, 1992. N 2-5
    - Londonas Latviešu Organizāciju Informācijas Biļetens. Londona, 1977. N 9, 10 (Flat-box 98, Folder 16)
    - Ziņu Vēsmas no Rinkona Misijas Bolīvijā. Nacogdoches, Texas, USA, 1984, August (Flat-box 98, Folder 17)
    - Latvian news digest: American Latvian Association in the United States, Inc., Information Bureau publication. Rockville, Md, 1986. N 3 (Flat-box 98, Folder 18)
    - CEDRAS Ziņas: Centrāle Etnogrāfijai, Dokumentācijai, Rādītājiem un Archīvam. Ormond Beach, Florida, 1990. N 9, 1991. N 10 (Flat-box 98, Folder 18)
    - Tautas Kopa Brīvība. Rīga, 1998 (Flat-box 98, Folder 18)
    - Līvli: Valsts Īpaši Aizsargājamās Kultūrvēsturiskās territorijas "Livod rānda" ("Lībiešu Krasts") mēnešraksts. Rīga, 1998. N 1, 2 (Flat-box 98, Folder 19)
    - Latvian Weekly "Laiks". Ņujorka, 1949. N 1 (Flat-box 96, Folder 8)
    - Latvian Weekly "Laiks". Ņujorka, 1965, 1966, 1976 (Box 99, Folder 1)
      1965. N 66, 1966. N 68, 69, 72, 1976. N 84, 85, 86, 2000. N 13
- Series 12. Photographs
  - Photoalbum about the return of Latvian refugees: Latvijas bēgļu atgriešanās. Latvijas Bēgļu re-evakuācijas Biedrība. Rīga, 1922 (Flat-box 100, Box 1)
  - Rev. Zariņš' private and family photographs, 1934-1992 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Rev. Zariņš' private and family photographs, 1976-2000 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - New York Latvian society, the beginning of the 20th century (Flat-box 101, Folder 1)
  - New York Latvian society, 1924-1943 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - New York Latvian society: Old Latvians: Tukschin family, 1922-1952 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - First Latvian pastors in New York: brothers Steiks, Rev. Carl Podiņš, 1872-1952 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Latvians in DP camp: Rendsburg, Schleswig-Holstein, Germany, undated (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Rev. Zariņš' first years in New York: parish activities, 1946-1959 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Latvian Relief, Inc., 1948-1950 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Parish activities: 1960-ties (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Parish activities: 1970-ties (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Parish activities: 1980-ties (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Parish activities: 1960-ties to 1980-ties, undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Parish activities: 1990-ties (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Children and youth activities: Sunday school, summer camps, scouts and guides etc., 1949-1982 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Confirmation, 1940-1960 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Confirmation, 1961-1970 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Confirmation, 1971-1989 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Cultural life: concerts, theater and art, 1946-1980 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Annual Women's International Expositions. Latvian folk art and designs, 1949-1982 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Political activities, 1949-1993 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Ambassador's Kārlis Zariņš visit to Rome, October 1950 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Prelate Jāzeps Čamanis. Refugee Aid Committee in Rome, 1947-1954 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    Jāzeps Čamanis (1884-1964), representative for the protection of the interests of Latvian citizens in Italy (without official status)
  - Latvian Memorial park and a cemetery in Catskills, 1977-1995 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Lettonia, 1955-1982 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, 1953-1986 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church in exile: Archbishop Teodors Grīnbergs (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church in exile: Dean Edgars Bergs (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Archbishop Elmars Ernsts Rozitis (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - New York Latvian Catholic Church, 1951-1989 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - History of Latvian Lutheran Church in Latvia, 1928-1955 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Bishop Kārlis Irbe, 1861-1934 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Latvia and Rīga: 1920-ties to 1940-ties (Box 103, Folder 12)